<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The court and kingdoms in tears: or, the sorrowful subjects lamentation for the death of her Majesty Queen Mary [w]ho departed this life, the 28th. of December, 1694; to the unspeakable grief of his Majesty, and all his loyal and loving subjects. To the tune of, If love's a sweet passion, &amp;c.</title>
            <title>Court and kingdom in tears.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B20756</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99884778</idno>
  <idno type="VID">192898</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2264208606</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C6584B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.20.f.9[503]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R217307</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99884778</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99884778e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B20756)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 192898)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; A6:1[299])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The court and kingdoms in tears: or, the sorrowful subjects lamentation for the death of her Majesty Queen Mary [w]ho departed this life, the 28th. of December, 1694; to the unspeakable grief of his Majesty, and all his loyal and loving subjects. To the tune of, If love's a sweet passion, &amp;c.</title>
                  <title>Court and kingdom in tears.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>A slip-song.</note>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing, which has publication date = [1694]; since Mary died 28 December, this is questionable.</note>
                  <note>Printed in one column.</note>
                  <note>Verse: "In Mourning, in Mourning the Kingdoms [sic] appears,".</note>
                  <note>Copy cut and mounted.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: mutilated, affecting text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Mary --  II, --  Queen of England, 1662-1694 --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Ballads, English --  17th century.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng" type="poem">
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:192898:1"/>
            <head>The Court and Kingdoms in Tears: Or, The Sorrowful Subjects Lamentation for the Death of her Majesty Queen MARY <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ho departed this Life, the 28th. of <hi>December,</hi> 1694; To the Unspeakabse Grief of his Majesty, and all his Loyal and Loving Subjects.</head>
            <opener>To the Tune of, <hi>If Love's a sweet Passion,</hi> &amp;c.</opener>
            <lg>
               <l>IN Mourning, in Mourning the Kingdoms appears,</l>
               <l>And the Eyes of true Subjects are flowing with Tears,</l>
               <l>For our Grief and our Sorrow, alas, it is great,</l>
               <l>Since our Gracious Queen <hi>Marie</hi> departed of late;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>By the hand of cold Death she was snatch'd from the Throne,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Having left our most gracious King</hi> William <hi>alone.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The loss of our Queen, we have cause to lament,</l>
               <l>In the prime of her Years, from the World she is sent,</l>
               <l>While her Sorrowful Subjects, do weeping complain,</l>
               <l>Knowing that they shall never behold her again:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>By the hand of cold Death,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               <l>O! what an unspeakable Change is there wrought?</l>
               <l>From a Throne, Crown and Septer, Q: <hi>M:</hi> is brought,</l>
               <l>For to take up her Lodging, now, now in the Grave;</l>
               <l>So uncertain is Honour and all that we have:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>By the hand of cold Death,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               <l>She in the Kings absence, did Govern the Realm,</l>
               <l>With Discreation and Wisdom, she sat at the Helm,</l>
               <l>While her Subjects in Loyal Obedience did stand,</l>
               <l>For a publict Blessing she was to the Land;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>To our Sorrow and Grief she is snatch'd from the Throne,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And our Monarch King</hi> William, <hi>now Governs alone.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>There's nothing but Sorrow and Grief to be seen,</l>
               <l>Thro' the Court and the Kingdoms for loss of the Q:</l>
               <l>Who in less than a week, was Alive, Well, and Dead;</l>
               <l>And with her all our Joyes and our Comforts are fled:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>By the hand of cold Death,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               <l>O! who would have thought, when from <hi>Flanders</hi> he came,</l>
               <l>And the Queen she did meet him in Triumph and Fame,</l>
               <l>That her time was so near, yet, alas, it is so.</l>
               <l>She is gone and hath left us in Sorrow and Wo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>By the hand of cold Death,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               <l>The learned Physitian was sent for with speed</l>
               <l>She was dangerous ill, there was never more need;</l>
               <l>But, alas, all the Skill in the World was in vain,</l>
               <l>For the Doctors they could not restore her again:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>By the hand of cold Death,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               <l>Her Soul is convey'd to the Regions of Joy,</l>
               <l>Where there's nothing her Comfort and Peace can annoy,</l>
               <l>It is we that are left in sad sorrowful Fears,</l>
               <l>For the loss of a Queen in the prime of her Years;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>By the hand of cold Death,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               <l>For gracious King <hi>William</hi> let's send up our Prayers.</l>
               <l>That the LORD would support him in all his Affairs;</l>
               <l>That he still may be able our Laws to defend,</l>
               <l>He has been to the Nation a Fatherly Friend;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Therefore Heaven, we hope, will establish his Throne,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>In the spight of his Foes, tho' he Governs alone.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>